[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 21]
[제21화]
I wanted to form a cultivation partnership with Lifei,
저는 려비와 도려를 맺고 싶었고
but I feared that my uncle wouldn't agree.
백부님께서 윤허하지 않으실까 봐
She panicked
려비가 급한 마음에
and went straight in to ask why.
직접 여쭤보러 간 겁니다
Since both Lei Xiuyuan and Ji Tongzhou
뇌수원과 기동주가
want to vouch for Jiang Lifei,
모두 강려비를 위해 증언하고 있으니
we can test whether these three
과연 이 세 사람이 거짓을 말하는지
are lying.
시험해 보면 진위가 드러날 것이오
My disciple and Jiang Lifei were indeed with me.
내 제자와 강려비는 줄곧 나와 함께 있었소
Are you going to interrogate me as well?
설마 도우께서는 나까지 심문하시겠다는 것이오?
Xiuyuan!
수원
Sir, what is this?
사백님, 어찌 이러십니까?
What have I done to offend you?
제가 무슨 죄라도 지었습니까?
My eyes must have been playing tricks on me just now.
내가 잠시 눈이 흐렸던 모양이구나
Maybe I was mistaken.
너를 오해했던 것 같구나
Everyone,
여러분
we've found the culprit!
드디어 장본인을 찾아냈습니다
Mr. Shi!
시 어르신
Shi Chengtian,
시승천
tell everyone about your dealings
마족과 결탁한 추악한 죄행을
with the demons!
이제 만인 앞에서 자백하거라
You're lying!
허튼소리 마오
When did I ever collude with demons?
내가 언제 마족과 결탁했다는 것이오?
This monster-bewitching powder
이것은 네게서
was found on you.
압수한 혹요분이다
Still denying it?
아직도 발뺌할 셈이냐?
You...
아니
Impossible!
그럴 리 없소
I used up that powder long ago!
그 가루는 진즉에 다 써버렸거늘
You're framing me!
이것은 명백히 날 모함하는 것이오
This is a setup! A frame-up!
이건 모함이고, 누명을 씌우는 것이오
Everyone.
여러분, 여러분
Mr. Shen.
문주님
He's the one who colluded with demons.
마족과 결탁한 것은 이자입니다
It's got nothing to do with us.
저희와는 아무런 상관이 없습니다
We were just trying to make some money.
저희는 그저 돈이나 좀 벌어 보려 했을 뿐입니다
Right, right.
맞습니다
That person in red said
그 붉은 옷을 입은 자가
that if we drove the beasts mad,
요수들을 미치게만 만들면
we could
저희가 당당히
kill them openly and sell them for money.
그들을 잡아 팔아 거금을 벌 수 있다고 했습니다
Person in red?
붉은 옷을 입은 자라고?
Yes, yes.
맞습니다
Someone!
여봐라
Take Shi Chengtian and that man away!
시승천과 그 수하들을 즉시 압송하여
Keep them under tight watch!
엄히 가두도록 하라
Wait, I...
아니, 저, 이건...
- It's got nothing to do with me. - Shen...
- 저와는 무관합니다 - 심...
It's nothing to do with me!
정말 저와는 상관없는 일입니다
Mercy!
살려 주십시오
It's got nothing to do with me!
저와는 상관없는 일입니다
Have mercy!
제발 살려 주십시오
That person in red Shi Chengtian mentioned
시승천이 말한 붉은 옷을 입은 자는
must be a demon Guardian.
필시 마족의 호법을 뜻하는 것이오
It's Rakshasa.
나찰이오
I fought her last night.
본좌가 어젯밤 직접 맞서 싸웠소
So Rakshasa is behind all this.
과연 모든 흉계는 나찰의 소행이었군
Demons are cunning and treacherous.
마족은 음험하고 교활하여
Hard to guard against.
대비하기가 실로 어렵소
From now on, we need to be extra careful
앞으로는 더욱 경계를 늦추지 말고
and watch out for demons sneaking in.
마족이 잠입하여 소란을 일으키지 못하도록 해야 하오
Given Shi Chengtian's strength,
시승천의 보잘것없는 공력으로는
he couldn't have helped a demon escape the city.
마족을 성 밖으로 무사히 빼돌릴 수는 없었을 것이오
We still need to find out
진정한 첩자가 누구인지는
who the real inside contact is.
아직 철저히 조사해 보아야 하오
After last night's city-wide sweep,
어젯밤 성안을 샅샅이 수색했으니
the demons wouldn't dare stay.
마족도 감히 성안에 머물지 못하고
They've probably fled by now.
이미 달아났을 것이오
Facing such a massive threat,
강적이 도사리고 있는 만큼
we must stand together.
우리는 한마음으로 맞서 싸워야 하오
That was the whole point of this Shanhai Gathering.
그것이야말로 이번 산해초회의 본뜻이오
Elder Cuixuan! This is bad!
사백님, 큰일 났습니다
Sir,
취현 사백님
Wuyue Court just sent an urgent message.
방금 무월정에서 긴급 전갈이 도착했습니다
A demon spy broke into Hushe Peak.
마족의 세작들이 호사봉을 돌파해 침입했다고 합니다
Sir,
사백님
does Wuyue Court have a Hushe Peak?
무월정에 호사봉이라는 곳이 있었습니까?
Quiet.
입 다물거라
No more questions.
쓸데없는 것을 묻지 말라
All Wuyue Court disciples,
무월정의 모든 제자는
return with me immediately.
즉시 무월정으로 귀환하도록 하라
Sir,
취현 선배님
Jiang Lifei and Lei Xiuyuan
강려비와 뇌수원은
were my friends at the academy.
서원에서 함께한 벗들입니다
I'd like them to stay a few more days
며칠 더 이곳에 머물며
so I can ask how things are going there.
지난 이야기도 나누고 싶습니다
Cuixuan.
선형
Duanming City has just settled down.
단명성이 이제 막 혼란을 수습한 터라
We could use skilled disciples to help with defense.
법력이 뛰어난 제자들의 도움이 절실하오
Do me a favor
부디 내 체면을 보아
and let them stay a little longer.
저들이 당분간 남아 힘을 보태도록 허락해 주시오
Fine.
정 그렇다면
You two stay and help.
너희 둘은 남아 돕도록 하여라
Once Duanming City is secure,
단명성이 안정을 되찾는 대로
come back right away.
당장 사문으로 돌아오도록 하여라
[Duanming City Inn]
[단명성 객잔]
Are these demons everywhere at once?
마족은 머리가 셋에 팔이 여섯이라도 달렸단 말입니까?
Causing trouble here while ambushing us there.
이쪽에서 소란을 일으키고 저쪽에서 기습을 감행하다니요
But Deng and I had a deal.
그것은 제가 등 사형과 미리 짜 둔 계책이었습니다
If anything goes wrong,
상황이 심상치 않게 흘러가면
he'd come in right away.
곧바로 안으로 들이닥치기로
How is it?
어떠하셨습니까?
Not bad, right?
제법 자연스러웠지요?
Will they suspect something?
그러면 정체가 드러나지 않겠지요?
Relax.
걱정 마십시오
I've cleared it with my master.
사부님과도 미리 뜻을 맞추었으니
He'll play along.
안에서 호응해 주실 것입니다
Sorry to drag everyone into this.
다만 저 때문에 여러분까지 위험에 휘말리게 되었군요
What are you talking about?
무슨 그런 말씀을 하십니까
This is something we want to do too.
저희 또한 기꺼이 나서고자 한 일이었습니다
Gelin's right.
가림의 말이 옳소
We were born into the imperial bloodline
우리는 황족의 신분을 타고난 탓에
and have been hunted by Longming Sanctuary.
줄곧 용명좌의 추격과 암살 위협에 시달려 왔소
If it weren't for righteous people risking their lives to save us,
의로운 협객들께서 목숨 걸고 구해 주시지 않았다면
we wouldn't be here today.
오늘까지 살아남지 못했을 것이오
Now that
이러한 판국에
we're seeing such injustice,
또다시 천인공노할 불의를 보고도
how could we stand by?
어찌 모르는 척할 수 있겠소?
We worked well together
게다가 모두의 손발이 척척 맞은 덕분에
and got out clean.
무사히 위기를 넘길 수 있었소
I always thought Mr. Zuo Qiu's talk
예전 좌구 선생님께서 늘 일러 주시던
about serving the people
세상을 구하고 백성을 보살피며
and purifying the world
호연지기로 천지를 바로 세우라는 말씀이
was just empty words.
그저 허울 좋은 말인 줄만 알았습니다
Now I see
이제야 비로소 깨달았습니다
how hard it is to stand up to power
권세에 굴하지 않고 대의를 행하는 일이
and fight for what's right.
얼마나 어렵고 험난한 길인지를 말입니다
Hard as it was, we did it.
하나 아무리 험난해도 끝내 해내지 않았습니까?
Come on!
자
Everyone,
여러 소협들
we've triumphed.
우리의 승리를 축하하며
Time for a good drink.
큰 잔으로 한잔 나눕시다
- Here. - Cheers!
- 잔을 드시지요 - 건배
What a shame.
참으로 안타깝군요
Here.
자
These sects are divided.
우리 각 문파의 뜻이 이토록 하나로 모이지 못하니
With a little provocation from the demons,
마족이 조금만 이간질을 해도
we fall apart
이처럼 갈라져
and turn on each other.
스스로 날개를 꺾고 마는군요
News reached my master, Sect Leader Miao.
제 사부이신 묘 장문께서 서신을 보내시어
He told Changyue and me to hurry back to Dizang Sect.
저와 창월더러 바로 지장문으로 돌아오라 하셨소
My uncle wants me back at Xingzheng Hall as soon as possible.
내 백부님께서도 조속히 성정관으로 돌아오라 하셨다
The demons sent only a single Guardian,
이번에는 마족이 호법 하나만 움직였을 뿐인데도
yet they threw Mountain and Sea Sects into utter chaos.
산해 양계가 이토록 큰 혼란에 빠졌으니
We can't underestimate them.
그 위세를 얕볼 수 없겠구나
He wants me back to train
하여 속히 돌아가 수련에 정진하여
so I'll be ready
훗날 해운이 닥칠 때
for the Sea Calamity.
강적과 맞설 힘을 기르라 하셨다
We barely had time to catch up,
회포도 다 풀지 못했는데
and now you're all leaving.
벌써 헤어질 때가 되었군요
Who knows
다음 만남은
when we'll see each other again?
언제가 될지 모르겠습니다
We'll cross that bridge when we get to it.
적이 오면 막고 물이 오면 흙으로 막는 법이지요
Next time we meet,
다음에 다시 만날 때는
it'll likely be the Sea Calamity.
어쩌면 해운의 재앙이 몰아치는 때일지도 모르겠소
Before that,
떠나기에 앞서
I'd like to ask you all for a favor.
여러분께 청 드릴 말이 하나 있소
Ever since I was little, I've known a girl.
어린 시절 한 낭자를 만난 이래
I think she's the most beautiful
그 아이가 이 세상에서 가장 아름답고
and lovely girl in the world.
가장 사랑스러운 여인이라 여겨 왔소
I've always wanted to marry her.
그 아이만을 아내로 맞이하리라 맹세했지요
We all know.
우리 모두 알고 있었습니다
You all are the dearest friends to Changyue and me.
여러분은 저와 창월이 가장 아끼고 믿는 사람이오
Before we part,
하여 이 이별의 자리에서
I want you all to witness this.
부디 우리의 증인이 되어 주십시오
Ye,
엽 오라버니
- you... - Changyue.
- 이게... - 창월
The Sea Calamity is coming.
해운의 재앙이 머지않았고
No one knows what lies ahead.
앞날을 예측할 수 없는 지금
Better to cherish the one beside you
후회만 남기기보다는
than to live with regret.
소중한 인연을 붙잡고 싶구나
Changyue,
창월
will you be my wife?
내 아내가 되어 주겠느냐?
My head hurts.
두통이 심하여
I'm going to my room to rest.
먼저 처소로 돌아가 쉬겠습니다
Changyue.
창월
I'll go check.
제가 가 보겠습니다
Tongzhou.
동주
During the Wanxian Sect's questioning today,
오늘 만선문에서 국문받을 때
you were quick on your feet.
참으로 반응이 빨랐습니다
You're getting almost as good at lying as I am.
즉석에서 지어내는 솜씨가 저 못지않더군요
Actually,
사실은
I wasn't entirely lying.
전부 거짓은 아니었다
Tongzhou,
동주
we made that three-year pact back at Lugong Town.
육공진에서 나누었던 삼 년의 약조를
How about we move it up?
차라리 지금으로 앞당기는 것은 어떠하오?
Sure.
좋다
We should've done this long ago.
나도 진즉 너랑 겨뤄 보고 싶었다
But I won't lose.
나는 절대 지지 않을 것이다
Tomorrow?
내일
At the Wu hour.
오시에 보자
Alright. Enough.
그만들 하십시오
Why fight?
왜 겨룹니까?
Aren't you tired?
피곤하지도 않아요?
Right now, the most important thing
지금 우리에게 가장 중요한 일은
is helping Ye Ye and Changyue
엽엽과 창월의
with their wedding.
혼례를 성사시키는 것입니다
If you really need to fight,
진정 무술을 겨루겠다면
wait until it's over
혼례가 마무리된 후에
and find a place to settle it.
알맞은 장소에서 겨루십시오
- Alright. - Fine.
- 좋다 - 그래
After Fanghu Island,
방호도의 사단을 겪으며
I suddenly realized
문득 깨달은 바가 있다
I can't wait any longer.
더는 기다릴 수 없다는 것을
Waiting any longer
이대로 시간을 더 지체하는 것은
would only hurt you and Gelin.
너와 가림 모두에게 상처만 줄 뿐이다
Time slips away
인생은 백구과극이라
in the blink of an eye.
순식간에 흘러가 버린다
I don't want to waste any more time.
더 이상 세월을 허비하고 싶지 않다
I want to be with you.
너와 함께하고 싶다
I want you to be my wife.
내 아내가 되어 주기를 바란다
- I want... - Enough, Ye!
- 나는... - 그만하세요, 엽 오라버니
Stop.
더는 말하지 마십시오
I said I needed time to think.
조금 더 생각할 시간을 달라고 말했잖아요
Gelin.
가림
Changyue.
언니
You should be discussing the wedding with Ye.
엽 오라버니와 혼례 이야기를 나누지 않고
Why are you looking for me?
왜 날 찾아왔어?
Gelin.
가림
Ye and I... I...
언니랑 엽 오라버니는...
Changyue.
언니
You seem smart,
언니는 겉보기에는 똑똑해 보이지만
but you're really clueless.
실은 꽤 허술한 사람이야
I used to worry
예전에는 엽 오라버니가
Ye wouldn't take good care of you.
언니를 제대로 보살피지 못할까 걱정했는데
Turns out I worried for nothing.
그것은 부질없는 기우에 불과했네
He takes great care of you.
오라버니는 언니를 지극정성으로 보살펴 주고 있으니
He's worth marrying.
언니가 평생을 맡길 만한 분이야
Gelin.
가림
I let you down.
언니가 참 미안해
Before, I was too caught up in my own things.
내 처지만 돌보기에 급급한 나머지
I thought you were still young,
네가 어리기만 한다고 생각해서
so I kept things from you.
속마음을 제대로 털어놓지 못했어
You ended up going all the way to the East Sea
그 때문에 네가 동해 그 먼 곳까지 가게 만들고
and suffering so much.
모진 고초를 겪게 하였으니
It's all my fault.
이 모든 것이 다 내 불찰이야
I'm sorry.
내가 미안하구나
Changyue,
언니
don't worry.
더는 걱정하지 마
I don't like Ye anymore.
난 이미 오래전에 엽 오라버니를 향한 마음을 접었어
Really.
진짜야
I like someone else now.
지금은 이미 마음에 품은 사람이 있어
I don't even remember those childhood things.
어릴 적의 풋사랑을 언제까지 품고 살겠어?
Gelin.
가림
Listen to me,
내 말을 들어봐
liking someone isn't a crime.
누군가를 연모하는 것은 결코 죄가 아니거늘
You didn't have to run so far away.
이토록 먼 곳으로 떠날 이유는 없었어
I really don't like him anymore.
이제는 정말 그분 안 좋아해
You don't have to turn him down because of me.
그러니 나 때문에 그분의 청혼을 거절하지 마
Ye was right.
엽 오라버니의 말이 맞아
Time slips away
인생은 덧없이 짧아
in the blink of an eye.
눈 깜짝할 새 흘러가니
We shouldn't waste any more time.
세월을 헛되이 보내서는 안 돼
I genuinely wish you two the best.
난 진심으로 언니와 오라버니를 축하해
Unless...
설마
Unless, after you get married,
언니와 오라버니가 혼인한 후에
you decide you don't want me anymore.
날 동생으로 받아들이지 않을 건 아니지?
What are you saying, silly girl?
무슨 말을 하는 거냐, 이 계집애야
Talking nonsense.
터무니없는 소리를 하는구나
Always talking nonsense.
터무니없는 소리를!
No matter where we are
우리가 어느 곳에 처해 있든
or how far apart,
아무리 멀리 떨어져 있더라도
I'll always miss you.
늘 너를 그리워할 것이며
And I believe you'll miss me too.
너 역시 나를 그리워할 거라 나는 믿어
We'll always be sisters,
우리는 그 어떤 풍파가 닥칠지라도
through life and death.
진정 생사를 함께할 유일한 자매니까
Gelin.
가림
What's wrong?
왜 그러냐?
Lifei said you went to Yingcui Island.
려비가 사형이 영취도로 떠났다 전하기에
I thought I'd never see you again.
다시는 보지 못할까 걱정했습니다
I thought you were all leaving
다들 이대로 영영
and never coming back.
돌아오지 않을 줄 알았습니다
I didn't want you...
나는 네가...
you all to worry.
너희가 염려할까 그랬습니다
You're hurt?
다치셨습니까?
Feeling better?
괜찮아지셨습니까?
Treasure it that much?
이토록 아끼시는 걸 보니
Did some special girl give it to you?
사형의 연인께서 정표로 주신 것인가 봅니다
It's the crest of the Jiufeng Clan.
이것은 우리 구봉족의 고유한 족휘다
Why no eyes?
어찌 눈동자가 없습니까?
Did you lose them?
떨어뜨려 잃어버리셨습니까?
You want to see the eyes?
눈을 보고 싶으냐?
Yeah.
네
It would look better
눈동자만 있으면
with eyes.
훨씬 아름다울 텐데요
This is...?
이건...
Now it has one.
이제 생겼다
What did you do?
지금 무엇을 하신 겁니까?
I swear by the Jiufeng Clan,
구봉족의 명예를 걸고 천지에 맹세하노니
I will never betray Baili Gelin.
이번 생이 다할 때까지 결코 백리가림을 배신하지 않을 것이며
Through life and death,
생사를 함께하고
we'll never part.
영원히 함께하겠습니다
Lu,
육 사형
are you crazy?
정녕 미치신 겁니까?
Take it off for me.
당장 거둬 주십시오
Once it's on, it can never be removed.
한번 끼우면 영원히 벗을 수 없다
Baili Gelin,
백리가림
you started this.
먼저 내 마음을 흔든 것은 너다
Come out.
나오라
My Lord,
이번 일을 통해
have you finally seen their true colors now?
존상께서는 저들의 추악한 본모습을 똑똑히 보셨습니까?
Stop using the demon clan.
더는 요족을 이용하지 말거라
Their situation
지금 저들의 처지가
is no different from yours 500 years ago.
오백 년 전의 너와 같지 않으냐?
My Lord, you remember me now?
존상께서 저를 기억해 내신 겁니까?
Your soul has been hiding in a bone-devouring butterfly.
혼령을 서골접에 기생시켜 가며
You've waited centuries
수백 년을 은인자중해 온 것이
for a result, haven't you?
결국 어떤 결말을 보기 위함이 아니더냐
The Sea Calamity is coming.
해운의 재앙이 임박했다
Instead of mutual destruction,
이대로 양패구상할 바에는
it's better to go home while you can.
지금이라도 돌아가는 편이 낫다
My Lord!
존상
Xiuyuan,
수원
thank you
참으로 고맙구려
for helping with the wedding.
내 혼례를 이토록 챙겨 주다니
I only hope that one day,
나 역시 네가
you can step out of being a stand-in.
하루빨리 대역이라는 신분에서 벗어나기를 바라오
But I still have a mission to fulfill.
다만 내겐 아직 짊어진 사명이 있소
Until it's done,
그 사명을 완수하기 전까지는
I can't afford a single wrong step.
한 걸음도 잘못 내디딜 수 없소
Mission?
사명이라니?
The true king of Gaolu
우리 고로국의 진정한 왕은
isn't named Ye,
엽 씨가
but
아니라
Yecha.
야차이시오
That Demon Lord?
그 마군을 말하는 것이오?
In ancient times,
상고 시절
when Yecha was still a Divine Lord,
야차께서 아직 신군이셨을 때부터
our ancestors followed him.
우리 선조들께서는 줄곧 그분을 보필해 왔소
A thousand years ago,
천 년 전
heaven's wrath descended.
천벌이 내렸을 때
The Ye clan was ordered to guard the Central Plains.
우리 엽씨 일족은 명을 받들어 중토를 수호해 왔지
Our duty is to find the Divine Lord
신군을 찾아내어
and end heaven's wrath.
천벌을 막는 것을 평생의 사명으로 삼아 왔소
That is our mission.
이것이 바로 우리의 사명이오
So
그러니
until it's fulfilled,
이 사명을 완수하기 전까지는
I don't even dare to die.
감히 죽을 수도 없소
Is the mission
사명이
really that important?
그토록 중요하단 말이오?
A true promise is etched in stone.
군자의 한 번 한 약조를
It can't be broken lightly.
어찌 쉬이 저버릴 수 있겠소
Not in a thousand years,
천 년, 만 년이 흐른다 해도
not in ten thousand.
결코 변할 수 없는 법이지요
Oh,
참
I saw
이번에 와서 보니
you and Lifei made up again.
그대와 려비가 예전처럼 화해한 듯하던데
So,
어떠하오?
are you two in love?
서로 마음을 확인한 거요?
I do like her.
내 마음은 그렇다만
But I don't know how she feels.
려비가 어떻게 생각하는지 모르겠소
Lifei seems happy enough.
내가 보기에는 려비 역시 꽤나 기뻐하는 눈치였으니
It's probably mutual.
그리 어긋나진 않을 것이오
Uncle.
백부님
I'd like to stay for Ye Ye's wedding
엽엽의 혼례를 마저 지켜본 후에
before returning to Xingzheng Hall.
성정관으로 복귀하고 싶습니다
Our highest techniques require cutting off attachments and desires.
우리 현문의 최고 선법은 반드시 정과 욕망을 끊어야 한다
If you don't focus on your training,
네가 이토록 수련에 전념하지 않는다면
how will you help your brother
어찌 장차 네 황형을 보필하여
secure the kingdom
사직을 수호하고
and achieve greatness?
대업을 이룰 수 있겠느냐?
Do I have to give up
대업을 이루기 위해서는
the one I love to achieve greatness?
마음에 품은 정인마저 포기해야 한다는 말씀입니까?
Remember who you are.
네 신분을 잊지 말거라
Can't a prince of the Yue State
월국의 영왕은
pursue the one he loves?
사랑하는 이조차 선택할 수 없단 말입니까?
To protect this kingdom,
이 나라의 사직과 강산을 지키기 위해서라도
you must master the Xuanhua Sacred Fire
너는 반드시 현화성화를 익혀
and attain immortality!
선신을 이루어야 한다
I don't need the Xuanhua Sacred Fire
저는 현화성화를 익히지 못해
or immortality
선신이 되지 못하여도
to protect the Yue State!
월국만은 끝까지 지켜낼 수 있습니다
Jiang Lifei's heart already belongs to another.
그 강려비의 마음속에는 이미 다른 이가 있거늘
Can't you see that?
그것이 보이지 않는단 말이냐?
Lifei has feelings for me.
려비의 마음속에는 분명 제가 있습니다
At worst, I'll give up my title as Prince
정 그렇다면 왕야의 자리 따위는 기꺼이 버리겠습니다
and abandon my path to immortality!
신선 수련도 더는 하지 않겠습니다
You!
네 이놈...
You...
네가 정녕...
Changyue,
창월
no bride in the world is more beautiful than you.
천하에서 가장 아름다운 신부가 바로 그대입니다
It's just this dress that's beautiful.
혼례복이 아름다운 덕분일 뿐입니다
Jiao prepared it.
심초 언니가 성심껏 준비해 주셨지요
She said
아초 언니가 말씀하시길
she'd give Lifei one when she gets married.
훗날 려비가 혼례를 올리시면 한 벌 선물해 주겠다 하셨습니다
So beautiful.
참으로 아름답구나
From the primal chaos,
천지가 처음 열리고
yin and yang were formed.
만물이 음양으로 나뉘었으니
Love between mortals
남녀의 아름다운 인연을
is passed down through rites and teachings.
예로써 이루게 하노라
Today, bound by ritual,
오늘 예를 갖춰 혼인을 이루고
they wed before these guests.
하객들 앞에서 그 맹세를 밝히노라
They share the ritual feast
음식을 함께 나누고
and drink the nuptial wine.
합환주를 나누어 마시도다
With heaven and earth as witness,
천지를 증인으로 삼고
under the sun and the moon.
일월로써 이름을 밝히나니
First bow to heaven and earth.
천지에 첫 번째 절을 올리라
Tongzhou!
사촌 오라버니
Lanya?
란아
what happened?
어찌 이러느냐?
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Wugou invaded the Yue State!
오구가 월국을 침공해
Duantu has fallen!
단도성이 함락되었습니다
- What? - What?
- 뭐라고? - 뭐라고?
Tonghe...
황제 오라버니
Tonghe was captured by Zong Quan!
황제 오라버니가 종권에게 잡히셨습니다
What?
뭐라고?
It was Zhijie.
지절이에요
He held off Longming Sanctuary
지절이 용명좌를 가로막아 준 덕에
so I could escape.
제가 간신히 탈출할 수 있었습니다
We're going back to Duantu right now!
당장 단도로 돌아가자
Don't act rashly.
충동적으로 움직여서는 안 된다
Since Zong Quan showed up,
종권이 친히 나선 것을 보면
Longming Sanctuary must have fully mobilized.
필시 용명좌가 전력을 기울였을 터
Let's return to Xingzheng Hall, gather the disciples,
우선 성정관으로 복귀하여 문도들을 소집한 뒤
and go rescue him together.
세력을 합쳐 구원에 나서는 것이 상책이다
Tongzhou!
동주
Are you ready?
채비는 끝마쳤습니까?
If you are, let's move.
준비가 되었다면 같이 움직입시다
The three of us will go to Duantu with you.
우리 셋이 동행하겠습니다
Ye Ye and Changyue are going back to Dizang Sect first,
엽엽과 창월은 우선 지장문에 들렀다가
then they'll meet up with us.
후에 우리와 합류하기로 하였습니다
Right.
그렇소
Longming Sanctuary is acting against all reason.
용명좌가 천리를 거스르는 만행을 저질렀으니
We'll report to our sect leader
우리가 장문께 이 사실을 고하고
and join forces with other sects
각 선문들을 규합하여
to stop them.
저들의 악행을 필히 저지할 거요
The situation is unclear.
전황이 불투명하니
You'll all be dragged into this.
자네들까지 화를 입을까 두렵다
If we can't
이 난세 속에서
watch out for each other in times like these,
서로를 지켜주고 도와주지 못한다면
what's the point of cultivation?
신선이 되기 위한 수련이 무슨 의미가 있겠소?
- Right. - Yes.
- 그렇습니다 - 맞소
How could this happen?
어찌 이 지경이 되었단 말인가
Mo Chen.
모진
Chen!
사형
Tongzhou.
사제
It was Longming Sanctuary.
용명좌의 소행이네
It was Zong Quan.
종권 그자가...
Move! Behave!
어서, 얼른 움직여라
- Go! - Keep up!
빨리 걸어라, 빠짝 따라가
Hurry!
속도를 내라, 서둘러
[Xingzheng Hall]
[성정관]
You must avenge
부디... 우리 원수를
us.
갚아 다오
Chen.
사형
No survivors.
단 한 명의 생존자도 없군요
It's been less than two years
우리가 종권에게 치명상을 입힌 것이
since we heavily wounded Zong Quan.
불과 두 해 전의 일인데
How did his cultivation recover so fast?
어찌 단시간에 공력을 회복했단 말입니까
Not just recovered.
이것은 그냥 회복한 것이 아니라
He seems even stronger.
더 흉포하고 강력해진 기세입니다
He wiped out
단 하룻밤 사이에
the entire Xingzheng Hall in a single night.
이 거대한 성정관을 멸문시키다니
What kind of evil art has he been practicing?
대체 어떤 요사스러운 사법을 연마했기에
Is it the Spirit-Devouring Canon?
설마 서령비전을 터득한 것인가?
After Gaolu fell,
과거 고로국 멸망했을 당시에도
Longming Sanctuary used every means
용명좌는 수단과 방법을 가리지 않고
to hunt down the imperial bloodline.
황족들을 유인하여 참살했었지
They'll use the same tricks again.
저들은 기필코 같은 수작을 반복할 것이야
[Yue State Imperial Palace]
[월국 황궁]
Tonghe.
황형
Are you alright?
무탈하십니까?
No.
안 됩니다
Tonghe!
황형
Don't leave me.
저를 두고 떠나지 마십시오
Tonghe. Tonghe!
황형, 황형
Tonghe.
황형
No!
안 됩니다
What a touching display of brotherly love.
과연 눈물겨운 형제애로구나
Prince Ying conspired with Xingzheng Hall to usurp the throne.
영왕이 성정관의 역도들과 결탁하여 대역부도를 도모하니
The Emperor of Yue is dead.
월국 황제가 마침내 붕어하였도다
How do you like my gift?
내가 친히 준비한 이 선물이 어떠하냐?
Zong Quan.
종권
I'll kill you!
내 네놈을 죽여 버릴 거다
Xuanhua Sacred Fire?
현화성화
What a pity.
안타깝구나
You haven't even mastered it.
네 수련이 아직 일천하여
You've only reached the second level.
겨우 제2층에 머물러 있다
Otherwise,
그렇지 않았다면
you might have traded a few strikes with me.
내가 친히 몇 합쯤은 겨루어 주었을 것을
You practice evil arts?
네놈이 감히 사법을 부리다니...
The law of this world is simple.
무릇 천지의 도란
The strong rule.
약육강식, 강자만이 존귀한 법이다
As long as you have the power to control everything,
천하를 손아귀에 쥘 절대적인 힘을 얻을 수만 있다면
the means don't matter!
그 수단이 무엇이든 간에 그리 중요치 않지
But
하나
I don't want to kill you yet.
아직 네놈의 목숨을 거둘 생각이 없다
Your spirit power is pure,
네 영력은 순수하고
and your constitution is excellent.
근골이 기이할 정도로 뛰어나니
You'll be useful to me.
내가 쓰기에는 더없이 안성맞춤이로구나
Tongzhou.
동주
Get Tongzhou out of here!
동주를 데리고 먼저 가거라
Let's go.
가자
Zhao Zhijie, are you insane?
조지절, 네가 미쳤구나
Zhao Zhijie?
조지절
They've all been controlled.
저들이 모두 술수에 조종당했소
Xuanhua Sacred Fire.
현화성화
Demon Annihilation!
주마
Lanya?
란아
Mr. Xuanshan!
백부님
Tongzhou!
동주
Are you alright?
괜찮으십니까?
Mr. Xuanshan. Mr. Xuanshan!
백부님, 백부님
Mr. Xuanshan, hang in there.
백부님, 버티십시오
Mr. Xuanshan.
백부님
Remember,
기억하거라
this is the fourth level of the Xuanhua Sacred Fire.
이것이 바로 현화성화 제4층
Incineration!
분세이니라
Mr. Xuanshan.
백부님
[Duantu City]
[단도성]
Let me go.
이거 놓아라
Let go!
놓지 못할까
A Xingzheng Hall disciple!
성정관의 제자구나
Perfect.
운이 좋군
Xu will reward us well.
서 사형께서 우리에게 큰 상을 내리실 거다
Hold him tight. Don't let him move.
단단히 결박하거라, 허튼짓 못 하도록
Lu.
육 사형
What's this thing for?
이것은 대체 무엇에 쓰는 것입니까?
It's Longming Sanctuary's puppet seal.
이것은 용명좌의 괴뢰인이다
Well...
아니...
Pup...
괴뢰...
Can it be removed?
이 술수를 풀 방도가 있습니까?
Yes, by pulling the puppet spider out.
체내의 괴뢰 거미를 뽑아내면 풀 수 있지만
But
다만
one wrong move
미세한 실수라도 범한다면
and it will backfire,
술법이 숙주를 역으로 덮쳐
snapping the host's neck.
숙주의 목이 부러져 즉사하게 된다
Mingli,
명례
after you got hurt on Fanghu Island,
지난번 방호도에서 부상을 입은 후에
didn't you go back to Xingzheng Hall early?
먼저 성정관으로 복귀하지 않았어요?
How did they catch you in Duantu?
어찌하여 단도에서 저들에게 잡힌 거예요?
When I returned from the East Sea,
동해에서 성정관으로 급히 돌아왔을 때는
I found Longming Sanctuary had ambushed Xingzheng Hall.
이미 용명좌가 성정관을 기습한 후였소
Behave!
얌전히 굴어라
Move it! Hurry!
빨리빨리 움직여, 어서
- Move! - Hurry!
서둘러라, 지체할 시간이 없다
I went to find my brother for help,
형님을 찾아 방도를 도모하려 했으나
but his house was empty.
집안은 이미 텅 비어 있었고
When I went to the Commandery Princess's Manor for news,
소식을 수소문하고자 군주부로 향했다가
I ran right into Longming Sanctuary's people.
용명좌와 정면으로 마주치고 말았소
Now their spies are everywhere.
현재 도처에 용명좌의 세작들이 깔려 있어
Still have no word from my brother.
형님의 행방조차 묘연하오
What about Prince Ying?
소왕야께서는 무사하시오?
Is he with you?
함께 계세요?
Uncle.
백부님
He'll pull through.
이 고비를 이겨내실 거야
Tongzhou,
동주
I pushed you into the fire today.
오늘 내가 너를 이토록 참혹한 화마 속으로 밀어 넣었으니
Will you hold it against me someday?
훗날 나를 원망하겠느냐?
No.
아닙니다
Uncle.
백부님
I won't defy you anymore.
다신 백부님의 말씀을 거역하지 않겠습니다
I'll listen to you.
백부님의 훈계를 따르겠습니다
I'll cut off attachments
속세의 정과 욕망을 끊어내고
and master the Sacred Fire.
필히 현화성화를 연마해 내겠습니다
Uncle.
백부님
Don't leave me.
저를 두고 떠나지 마십시오
You must live.
너는 살아남아야 한다
Live on for all eternity, in the name of the Yue State.
월국을 위해 천 년, 만 년을 살아다오
Uncle.
백부님
If you ever feel wronged or unhappy out there,
만약 밖에서 억울한 일을 당하거나 마음이 상하거든
come back to me.
망설이지 말고 이 형을 찾아오거라
Forget cultivation if it comes to that.
정 안 되면 수련 따위 때려치우면 그만이지
I'll support you.
이 형이 널 먹여 살리지 못하겠느냐
Got it.
알았습니다
I'm going.
이만 가보겠습니다
Tonghe.
황형
Tongzhou.
동주
The Yue State and Jingwu
월국과 경오를
are yours now.
이제 네게 부탁한다
No, Tonghe.
안 됩니다, 황형
No.
안 됩니다
Tonghe.
황형
Tongzhou.
동주
Lifei?
려비
Don't be scared.
무서워하지 마십시오
Be careful.
조심하세요
You're still hurt. Don't get too worked up.
지금 상처도 채 아물지 않았으니 흥분해선 안 됩니다
You've been unconscious for five days.
이번에 꼬박 닷새 동안이나 혼절하여 깨어나지 못하셔서
We were all so worried.
우리 모두 애가 타 죽는 줄 알았습니다
Five days?
닷새라니
All this time,
그동안
you've been channeling your own spirit power
네가 줄곧 자신의 영력을 소모해 가며
into me?
내게 영력을 불어넣어 준 것이냐?
It was Gelin and Xiuyuan.
가림과 수원이
They've been working day and night,
밤낮으로 쉬지 않고
setting up formations to repair your spirit meridians.
진법을 펼쳐 왕야의 영맥을 회복시켜 드렸습니다
Everything happened so fast.
모든 일이 너무도 갑작스러웠습니다
So much at once.
한꺼번에 너무 많은 변고가 닥쳐와
I couldn't even bring myself to come see you.
이 안으로 들어와 마주할 엄두가 나지 않았습니다
Scared?
두려웠느냐?
When we first escaped,
간신히 탈출해 나왔을 때
your meridians were shattered. You were barely clinging to life.
왕야의 영맥은 심하게 손상되어 숨이 끊어지기 직전이었습니다
Thankfully, Xiuyuan kept us all grounded.
다행히 수원이 모두의 마음을 다잡아 주었습니다
Since the Shanhai Gathering,
지난 산해초회 때부터
seeing so many people and spirits die,
수많은 인간과 요족이 쓰러지는 모습을 보고서야
I suddenly realized
비로소 깨달았습니다
even the strongest lives are so fragile.
아무리 강인한 생명이라도 이토록 허망하게 스러질 수 있다는 것을요
I was afraid we couldn't save you.
혹여 왕야를 살려내지 못할까 두려웠고
Afraid you'd give up and follow your family.
먼저 떠난 가족들의 뒤를 따르게 될까 봐 두려웠습니다
So,
그래서
I hid outside for days,
문밖을 수일이나 맴돌며
too scared to come in.
감히 안으로 들어오지 못했습니다
Until Xiuyuan said
수원이 왕야는 죽지 않을 것이라
you'd live.
제게 말해 줄 때까지 말입니다
What does it matter if I die?
죽는다 한들 무엇이 달라지겠느냐
I'd rather it had been me.
차라리 죽은 사람이 나였으면 좋았을 것을
I'm so useless.
난 이토록 무능하여
I couldn't protect anyone.
그 누구 하나 지켜내지 못하지 않았느냐
Why wasn't it me?
어찌하여 죽은 이가 내가 아니란 말이냐
Why am I the only one left?
어찌하여 나 홀로 이리 살아남았단 말이냐
Why only me?
왜 나만 살아 있는 것이냐고
Because there is someone who need you.
이 세상에는 왕야를 필요로 하는 이들이 남아 있기 때문이오
Xiuyuan.
수원
Tongzhou.
동주
You don't have time to grieve.
슬퍼할 시간조차 없소
Your brother was a great emperor.
황형은 참으로 성명하신 군주이셨더군요
Before Duantu fell,
단도성이 함락되기 직전
he managed to evacuate most of the people.
그분은 대다수의 백성들을 안전하게 대피시키셨소
But many soldiers were captured
하나 여전히 적지 않은 장졸들이 포로로 잡혀
and will be slaughtered.
참살당할 위기에 처해 있소
They are your people.
그들 모두가 왕야의 백성들이지 않소?
You have to shoulder the responsibility.
이제 그 책임을 짊어져야 하오
You don't have the right to give up.
왕야에게는 포기할 권리도 없으며
And you can't throw your life away.
죽음을 택해서도 안 되오
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪